Guide to the Ved Mehta Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 1996 Acquisition, circa 1924-1995; 68.25; (122 boxes)
  - Family Archives
    - Family Archives 1940s
      - A.R. Mehta to Mrs. Tigert: 1949 Marriage of Daughter (Box 93)
      - Fathers Application to World Health Organization, 1949 (Box 93)
    - Family Archives 1950s
      - Family Archives, 1955 (Box 93)
      - Family Archives, 1954 (Box 93)
      - Father's American Trip (correspondence), 1950-1951 (Box 93)
      - Daddyji, 1951-1956 (Box 93)
      - Manuscript: India in General, 1951 (Box 93)
      - Correspondence course, 1951 (Box 93)
      - Family Archives: extracts from History of Services by A.G. Punjab, 1951 (Box 93)
      - Daddyji's Population Essay (Box 93)
      - Report of a Mission to Ceylon, 1952 (Box 93)
      - Christmas, 1952 (Box 93)
      - Writing, 1952 (Box 93)
      - Ved's Diary Jan-April, 1952 (Box 93)
      - Summer, 1952 (Box 93)
      - "Outlook for India" broadcast, A.R. Mehta and Morning Advocate clipping (Box 93)
      - Daddyji International Conference on Population Control (Box 93)
      - Father: India on the March (Box 93)
      - Daddy's retirement (book), 1952 (Box 93)
      - American Foundation for the Blind, 1952-1953 (Box 93)
      - Christmas (Pomona), 1953 (Box 94)
      - Father's lectures in U.S., rough notes for The Stolen Light, 1952-1955 (Box 94)
      - Applications to Colleges, 1953 (Box 94)
      - Harvard (Yale etc. transfer), 1953-1956 (Box 94)
      - A-Series: Daddyji's copies of Ved's letters, 1953 (Box 94)
      - Daddyji's retirement (correspondence) and other correspondence of father, 1953 (Box 94)
      - Letter to Anne Lockwood, 1953 (Box 94)
      - American Foundation for the Blind, 1954 (Box 94)
      - Applications for Graduate School (Yale, Princeton, etc), 1954-1955 (Box 94)
      - Autobiographical-Series: Daddyji's copies of Ved's letters, 1954 (Box 94)
      - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 94)
      - Correspondence. Royal National Institute for the Blind, 1954 (Box 94)
      - Writing (Harvard), 1954-1955 (Box 94)
      - American Federation for the Blind, 1955 (Box 94)
      - Rhodes scholarship and other fellowship, 1955 (Box 94)
      - Letter to father (from Ved's brother?) Sept., 1955 (Box 94)
      - A-Series: Daddyji's copies of Ved's letters, 1955 (Box 94)
      - Letters to Anne Lockwood, 1955 (Box 94)
      - Kay Pomona friend who committed suicide; 1983 letter from Regina Shinn, his sister, R.I. College, 1955 (Box 94)
      - Harvard, 1955-1956 (Box 95)
      - Oxford, 1955-1956 (Box 95)
      - American Foundation for the Blind, 1956 (Box 95)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddyji's copies of Ved's letters, 1956 (Box 95)
      - Newspaper clippings about "World Affairs Council" (A.R. Mehta) Nov., 1956 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence: A.R. Metha to Benjamin Franklin (Lecture tour) (Box 95)
      - American Foundation for the Blind Education Fund, 1957-1959 (Box 95)
      - Letters to Anne Lockwood, 1957 (Box 95)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddy's copies of Ved's letters, 1957 (Box 95)
      - Clippings and reactions to Face to Face, 1957 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence Ved-Nancy Reynolds, of Atlantic Month Press, Jan-Feb, 1957 (Box 95)
      - Hazen Foundation Fellowship, 1956-57 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence: Ved-Father, Mrs. Clyde writing, 1958 (Box 95)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddyji's copies of Ved's letters, 1958 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence with English journals, 1958-66 (Box 95)
      - Letter to A.R. Mehta from D.P. Arnand, his nephew, 1958 (Box 95)
      - Applications to Yale and Harvard from Oxford, 1958 (Box 96)
      - Letters to Anne Lockwood (and her permission to use them), 1958-1959 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence with Indian Journals, 1959-1965 (Box 96)
      - Mrs. Clyde publications Father and Ved: newspaper clippings, 1959 (Box 96)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddy's copies of Ved's letters, 1959 (Box 96)
      - Daddyji retirement material, 1959 (Box 96)
      - Answers from Father (Box 96)
    - Family Archives 1960s
      - Daddyji American clippings, 1960 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence (Ved, Daddyji, Mrs. Clyde), 1960 (Box 96)
      - Letter to Anne Lockwood, 1960 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence (Ved, Daddyji, Mrs. Clyde), 1961 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence (Clyde, Ved, Daddyji) New Yorker, 1962 (Box 96)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddy's copy of Ved's letters, 1962 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence: New Yorker, 1963 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence: Vivian Wiggins Ethel, 1964 (Box 96)
      - Ethel, Daddyji, Braille, 1965 (Box 96)
      - Letters Ved-Father-Clyde, 1966-1969; 4 (Box 96)
    - Family Archives 1970s
      - Letters Ved-Father-Clyde, 1970 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence: Ved-parents for Mamaji, 1970s (Box 96)
      - Letters Ved-Daddy-Mrs. Clyde, 1971-1972; 2 (Box 96)
      - Letters Ved-Father-Clyde, 1974-1978; 5 (Box 96)
      - Correspondence: Ved-parents, 1978-1982 (Box 96)
      - Letters Ved-Father-Mrs. Clyde, 1979 (Box 96)
    - Family Archives - 1980s and Miscellaneous
      - Taken out of Autobiographical Series Ved's letters to Daddy, 1964-1970 (Box 96)
      - Autobiographical Series: Daddy's copies of Ved's letters, 1964-1970 (Box 96)
      - Checking: Thind Family, letter from Vivian, 1986 (Box 96)
      - Father's diaries (5 v.), 2 address books, 1949-1972; 2 (Box 97)
    - Used Family Papers
      - Urdu family papers, 1920s-1960s (Box 97)
      - Family document, horoscope (Box 97)
      - Durga Das (maternal grandfather) papers & correspondence, 1930s-1950s (Box 97)
      - Papers of Durga Das; school & college diplomas, Durga Das, 1950s-1970s (Box 97)
      - Causes: Punjabi language (Durga Das) (Box 97)
      - Babuji (Durga Das) Papers received from L.D. Mehra, 3 (Box 98)
      - Chacha's autobiography in Urdu (Box 98)
    - Family Archives undated
      - Ved Mehta Writings ["Diplomat", "Gin-Clear Water", "Ghandi and the South", "Notes and Comments", "Peacocks", "Dee-Deedle-Dee", Galleys for '91 India Piece, and unidentified writings], undated (Box 99)
      - Questionable Use, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Family archives Rejected for '59 Volume, undated (Box 99)
      - Babuji 1959 (see red-marked passages)/Dead (Box 99)
      - Introduction--Anand Marriages, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Rejected, undated (Box 99)
      - Babuji's Diary Commentary/Dead, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Mamaji (Illness)/Dead, 1958-1967 (Box 99)
      - Babuji, Bhatnagar's Translation, Pitaji (Durga Das) diary page, jewelry, prescriptions, family tree, and observation, 1959-1973, undated (Box 99)
      - Babuji Insert/Dead, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Introduction--Bhaji Ganga Ram, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Introduction--Simla life, Lahore House, etc., 1945-1949 (Box 99)
      - Introduction/Background, Umi's courtship with Gautman, 1949 (Box 99)
      - Introduction--Anand Parents, Bibi Parmeshevari (?) Devi's children, 1959 (Box 99)
      - Babuji's complete diary (Box 99)
      - Unidentified text in [Urdu?], undated (Box 99)
      - Early Manuscripts/ Daddyji / Correspondence, 1975 (Box 99)
      - Hazen Foundation history and activities, 1956 (Box 99)
      - Educational Fund 3rd Contribution, 1956-1957 (Box 99)
      - Educational Fund 4th Contribution, 1957-1959 (Box 99)
      - Face to Face: correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 99)
      - Usha, 2nd year, 1958 October (Box 99)
      - Holywell Manor, 1957 (Box 99)
      - Oxford Years, Balliol College, 1963-1966? (Box 99)
      - Oxford letters to TenBroek, 1956-1985 (Box 99)
      - Writings and correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 99)
      - Family correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 99)
      - Used Family papers (momentos): Babuji's copybook and wedding notebook, undated (Box 99)
      - Checkers: California piece, TenBroek, and Federation of the Blind (Box 99)
      - Notes on violence in portions of India, undated (Box 99)
      - Urdu couplets, undated (Box 99)
      - Watumull Foundation Papers, 1952-1972; 4 (Box 99)
      - Watumull Family history, 1979-1982 (Box 99)
      - Used family papers (mementos), 2 (Box 99)
  - Financial Records
    Boxes 100-114 (Financial records): Restricted until 2031.
    - Bank statements, 1956-1969; 10 (Box 100)
    - Bank statements, 1966-1986; 9 (Box 101)
    - Bank statements, 1979-1983; 10 (Box 102)
    - Bank statements, 1979-1982; 12 (Box 103)
    - Bank statements, 1956-1965; 12 (Box 104)
    - Bank statements, 1972-1975; 10 (Box 105)
    - Bills, 1959-1977; 8 (Box 106)
    - Bills, 1958-1983; 17 (Box 107)
    - Bills, 1982-1985; 10 (Box 108)
    - Bills, 1972-1974; 11 (Box 109)
    - Bills and receipts, 1978-1986; 11 (Box 110)
    - Bills, 1978-1979; 7 (Box 111)
    - Bills and other financial records, 1965-1972; 8 (Box 112)
    - Bills, 1968-1970; 3 (Box 113)
    - Chemical Custody Acct (Box 114)
    - Morgan Bank Acct (Box 114)
    - Brundage, Story, and Rose (Box 114)
    - Orders, 1981-1982; 2 (Box 114)
  - Clippings (Personal and related to Writings)
    - Sound Shadows of the New World (Box 115)
    - Three Stories of the Raj (Box 115)
    - Mamaji (Box 115)
    - My Poor Relation (Box 115)
    - The Photographs of Chachaji (Box 115)
    - Personal, 1957-1994; 34 (Box 115)
    - Pomona, 1952-1956 (Box 115)
    - Personal, 1949-1956; 7 (Box 115)
    - Personal, Arkansas school, 1949-1952 (Box 115)
    - Face to Face (Box 115)
    - Scrapfolder (Box 115)
    - The New India, Television: duplicate clippings, 2 (Box 115)
    - John is Easy to Please: duplicate clippings (Box 115)
    - Gandhi: duplicate clippings (Box 115)
    - Daddyji: duplicate clippings (Box 115)
    - Portrait of India: duplicate clippings (Box 115)
    - New Theologian, 1966 (Box 116)
    - Delinquent Chacha, 1967 (Box 116)
    - Fly and the Fly Bottle, 1963 (Box 116)
    - Walking the Indian Streets, 1960 (Box 116)
    - Face to Face, 1957 (Box 116)
    - Personal Duplicates, 1955-1977 (Box 116)
    - To Send Out, 1962 (Box 116)
    - New India, TV: duplicate clippings, 1978 (Box 116)
    - Duplicates of writings, 1962-1974 (Box 116)
    - Fly and the Fly Bottle, 1963-1967 (Box 116)
    - Commonweal (4 copies), 1972 January 14 (Box 116)
    - Duplicate clippings, 1960-1982 (Box 116)
    - Miscellaneous, 1960-1964 (Box 116)
    - Writings: Clippings in Foreign Languages (Box 117)
    - R. Gandhi and Rama's Kingdom: [England] (Box 117)
    - R. Gandhi and Rama's Kingdom: [U.S.A.] (Box 117)
    - R. Gandhi elsewhere [India] (Box 117)
    - R. Gandhi: duplicates (Box 117)
    - Scrapbook 1949 (copy) (Box 117)
    - Up at Oxford [England] (Box 117)
    - Up at Oxford: Duplicate Reviews?, 4 (Box 117)
    - Fly Bottle Library Squibs, etc. (Box 117)
    - Portrait of India [U.S.A] (Box 117)
    - Portrait of India [various] (Box 117)
    - Walking the Indian streets [Britain, India, Commonwealth] (Box 117)
    - Walking the Indian streets [U.S.A] (Box 117)
    - The Ledge Between the Streams [U.S.A.] (Box 117)
    - The Ledge Between the Streams [Britain] (Box 117)
    - The Ledge Between the Streams [India], 1984 (Box 117)
    - Mamaji: reviews [U.S.A] (Box 118)
    - Mamaji: reviews [Britain]
    - Mamaji (Box 118)
    - Mahatma Gandhi [India] (Box 118)
    - Mahatma Gandhi (Box 118)
    - Delinquent Chacha [India, U.S., Britain] (Box 118)
    - Vedi (Box 118)
    - Duplicate Clippings, 3 (Box 118)
    - Daddyji (Box 118)
    - "John is Easy to Please" [U.S.] (Box 118)
    - "John is Easy to Please" [U.K., India] (Box 118)
    - The New Theologian [U.S., U.K.] (Box 118)
    - A Family Affair, [Britain, U.S. India] (Box 118)
    - The New India (Box 119)
    - "The Stolen Light" (Box 119)
    - "Flybottle" reviews [U.S.A] (Box 119)
    - "Flybottle" reviews [Britain, India] (Box 119)
  - Oversize
    - New Yorker proofs of City of a Dreadful Night, 7 (Box 120)
    - "In the Force & Road of Casualty", Reader's proofs, 1993 (Box 120)
    - "In the Force & Road of Casualty", Checker's proofs - July 16 & 20, 1993 (Box 120)
    - Mamaji: reviews [Britain] (Box 120)
    - Autobiographical Series: Leonardo Society photograph (Box 120)
    - Scrapbooks, 2 (Box 121)
  - Electronic Files and Audiovisual Material
    - Computer disks (from Box 17)
      - Chapter 6 Ch 7 Insert File, 1996-genm-0701-a-0004; 1 (Box 122)
        Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Computer disks (from Box 37)
      - SINGLE SIDED APPLE MAC WORD.3, 1996-genm-0701-a-0005; 1 (Box 122)
      - Oxford Material Data #1 done by Heather (306) 586-4591 Wordperfect 4.2, 1996-genm-0701-a-0006; 1 (Box 122)
      - Oxford Material Data #2 done by Heather (306) 586-4591 on Wordperfect 4.2, 1996-genm-0701-a-0007; 1 (Box 122)
        General
        Former child record (uri=/repositories/11/digital_objects/87958 - title=1996-genm-0701-a-0007) was deleted from catalogue on [Thu Apr 04 15:51:52 EDT 2019] as matching Preservica null f4c1aa13-8d40-4255-915d-bb8958eb4131 was deleted.
    - Computer disk (from Box 68)
      - MEHTA Rajiv Gandhi (3/15), 1996-genm-0701-a-0008; 1 (Box 122)
    - Computer disk (from Box 75)
      - [no label information], 1996-genm-0701-a-0009; 1 (Box 122)
- July 1999 Acquisition, circa 1957-1998; 6.01; (14 boxes)
  Purchased from Ved Mehta on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1999.
  Formerly classed at Uncat MS Vault 860.
  Drafts and working files for writings.
  - New Yorker Book: Checking chapters 1-9, 1960-1993 (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence Elsewhere checking 1959-1966 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Correspondence checking 1963-1964 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence checking 1962 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence USA checking 1963 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence USA checking 1965 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - New Yorker Book checking from 1962 envelope (valise), undated (Box 123)
  - Frederick Mulhauser checking from Pomona 1974 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Philosophy correspondence with subjects 1962 checking Chapter 6 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Philosophy 1962 Chapter 6 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Silvers checking 1962 (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Weeks checking 1978 (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Correspondence "Fly" checking 1962-1963 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Men, Meat and Miracles, by Bertram B. Fowler: printed version (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Shreve Trust checking 1959 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Gottleib checking 1987 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Theologians checking 1965-1966 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - History piece checking 1961-1962 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Homecoming, Joseph Wechsberg checking, undated (Box 123)
  - Eichmann checking 1963 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Indian Summer checking 1959 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Indian Summer libel correspondence checking 1960 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Matthews Review of Walking the Indian Streets 1960 (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Walking the Indian Streets Correspondence 1960-1971 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence checking 1962 (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal family correspondence India checking 1956-1964 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence India checking 1958-1966 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Personal correspondence USA checking 1961 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Shawn checking 1959-1966 (copies), undated (Box 123)
  - Philosopy piece ("Words, words, words") (copy), undated (Box 123)
  - Wolfe correspondence, 1965-1988 (Box 124)
  - Wolfe clippings, 1965-1995 (Box 124)
  - Wolfe radio transcripts (copies), undated (Box 124)
  - Harvard checking 1958-1959 (includes copies), 1959, undated (Box 124)
  - Harvard insert checking 1959-1970 (copies), undated (Box 124)
  - Father buys stocks in New York for Ved checking, 1957 (Box 124)
  - L. Ross adoption checking Chapter 6 1960 (copies), undated (Box 124)
  - Ideal Editor/ Hollands Diep interview checking (copy), undated (Box 124)
  - India travel diary checking 1965-1966, undated (Box 124)
  - Portrait of India checking: material not used (copies), undated (Box 124)
  - Under a Tolerant Roof checking 1958-1997 (including copies), 1997, undated (Box 124)
  - Early Tremors and Shocks checking 1979-1987 (copies), undated (Box 124)
  - Jonathan Schell's corrections and notes, 1997 (Box 124)
  - The Succession Problem checking, 1985 (Box 124)
  - Being Honor Bred checking, 1985 (Box 124)
  - Aftermath checking, 1987 (Box 125)
  - Gottlieb checking, 1987 (Box 125)
  - Jonathan Schell: article, notes, comments ("Our local correspondents"), 1987 (Box 125)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker
    - Epilogue, 1992-1993; 3 (Box 125)
    - Untitled re New Yorker: typescript, undated (Box 125)
    - Woolly manuscript, 1996 (Box 125)
    - Shawn manuscript pp. 1-40, undated (Box 125)
    - Chapter 10: Being Honor Bred, typescript, undated; 3 (Box 126)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: manuscript [2 copies], undated; 8 (Box 127)
      Includes 3 computer disks.
      Electronic files available through Access Services (Disks #1, #2, #3).
  - The Stolen Light
    - Setting copy, 1988; 2 (Box 128)
    - Setting copy, 1989; 4 (Box 128)
    - Galleys, 1988 June 20; 3 (Box 128)
    - Foul matter: page proofs and galleys, 1988-1989; 7 (Box 129)
  - Up at Oxford
    - New Yorker piece/galleys. "In the Force and Road of Casualty", 1993 May 3 (Box 130)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker (Box 130)
    - Draft, undated; 3 (Box 130)
    - Correspondence (copies), 1962-1970; 3 (Box 130)
    - Correspondence (copies), 1971-1979; 2 (Box 131)
    - New Yorker obituaries and editorial personnel, 1973 Nov (Box 131)
    - Research material, undated; 9 (Box 131)
    - Halcyon Days-Part One, 1997 Jan 22; 2 (Box 132)
    - Checking Shawn book, 1966-1969, undated; 7 (Box 132)
    - Naomi Grob. Revisions of "Politics of Sanitation", 1994 Apr 20 (Box 132)
  - Rajiv Gandhi and Rama's Kingdom
    - Setting copy, Yale University Press, 1994; 2 (Box 133)
    - Yale University Press proofs, 1994 (Box 133)
    - Personal manuscript-excision from Chapter 1 of Amantya Sen's reader's report of 31 October 1993 (Box 133)
    - Personal manuscript, 1993 (Box 133)
    - Personal manuscript (with Eleanor Gould's last revisions), 1993 November; 2 (Box 133)
    - Last fixes Gould, Moni, Inder, 1993-1994 (Box 133)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker
    - Third proof, 1998 February (Box 134)
    - Final proofs. 2nd pass Galleys. Atlantic page proofs, 1998 February 12 (Box 134)
    - Consolidated changes of Mehta and Gould. Revised on December, 27, 1997. Backup copy, 1997 December 27 (Box 134)
    - Mehta changes sent to Gould, 1997 December (Box 134)
    - Penultimate version, 1997 November 28 (Box 134)
    - Atlantic Monthly with excerpt, 1998 April (Box 134)
    - Manuscript draft (another penultimate), 1997 October 1; 2 (Box 134)
    - Manuscript penultimate draft, 1997 September 11 (Box 135)
  - A Ved Mehta Reader. The Art of the Essay (Box 135)
    - Proofs: duplicate set, 1998 (Box 135)
  - Computer media
    Computer disks from box 127.
    - "REMEMBERING MR. SHAWN…" (latest, w/changes) 9/22/97, 1999-genm-0701-a-0001; 1 (Box 136)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker latest version 10/30/97 Final Draft w.out changes, 1999-genm-0701-a-0002; 1 (Box 136)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's Nyer 11.21.97, 1999-genm-0701-a-0003; 1 (Box 136)
- February 2000 Acquisition, 1958-1999; 5.21; (12 boxes)
  Purchased from Ved Mehta on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2000.
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 9.
  Working files and correspondence files for writings.
  - Book Royalities, 1982-1998; 12 (Box 137)
  - Book Royalties, 1967-1981; 3 (Box 138)
  - Book: Oxford correspondence, 1986-1992; 3 (Box 138)
  - Book: Oxford correspondence, 1993; 3 (Box 139)
  - Book: New India of Indira Gandhi correspondence, 1977-1990 (Box 140)
  - Book: Mamaji correspondence, 1976-1995; 2 (Box 140)
  - Book: The Ledge Between the Streams correspondence, 1983-1999; 2 (Box 140)
  - Book: Three Stones of the Raj correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 141)
  - Theologian recipient list, undated (Box 141)
  - Book: The Stolen Light correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 141)
  - Sound Shadows of the New World correspondence, 1985-1995 (Box 141)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: "Gould chapters", undated (Box 141)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker correspondence, 1998 (Box 141)
  - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: correspondence, 1995-1997; 4 (Box 142)
  - Mehta Reader, correspondence, 1997-1998; 2 (Box 142)
  - New Yorker manuscript: [Cravens?] revisions, 1997-1998 (Box 142)
  - New Yorker manuscript: Liz Macklin's changes, 1997 (Box 143)
  - New Yorker manuscript: Packard's changes (Box 143)
  - Archives Post Yale ("History section from the New Yorker book"), 1996-1997; 3 (Box 143)
  - Book: Rajiv Gandhi, correspondence, 1993-1997; 2 (Box 143)
  - Portrait of India, correspondence, 1971-1972; 3 (Box 144)
  - Book: Vedi. Correspondence, 1972-1982; 3 (Box 145)
  - Walking, correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 145)
  - Daddyji, correspondence, 1972-1988; 2 (Box 145)
  - Delinquent Chacha, correspondence, 1966-1993; 2 (Box 146)
  - Face to Face, correspondence, 1958-1998; 2 (Box 146)
  - A Family Affair, correspondence, 1981-1999 (Box 146)
  - Fly and the fly-bottle, correspondence, 1962-1988; 2 (Box 147)
  - Fly and the fly-bottle, Foreign rights, 1995 (Box 147)
  - Fly and the fly-bottle, reprint, 1982 (Box 147)
  - Fly and the fly-bottle, reprints, 1966 (Box 147)
  - Gandhi correspondence, 1971-1976; 3 (Box 147)
  - Gandhi correspondence, 1976-1993; 2 (Box 148)
  - India correspondence, 1965-1967; 2 (Box 148)
  - John is Easy to Please, correspondence, 1970; 2 (Box 148)
- March 2005 Acquisition, circa 1952-2005; 23.48; (52 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
  Purchased from Ved Mehta on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2005.
  Formerly classed as Uncat MSS 759.
  - Writings and Research Files
    - All for Love
      - Earlier version, undated; 3 (Box 149)
      - Draft 3, 1999 October 27; 3 (Box 149)
      - Second version, 2000 November 12; 3 (Box 150)
      - British setting, 2001 February 15; 3 (Box 150)
      - British proofs, final pages sent to Granta, [2001] March 28; 4 (Box 151)
      - Draft, circa 2000; 3 (Box 151)
      - Drafts, last copy pre-Terry McGary, 2001; 2 (Box 152)
      - Liz Macklin's copy-edited manuscript, 2002; 2 (Box 152)
      - First draft, 4 (Box 152)
      - Kiltykins (Box 153)
      - Prologue (Box 153)
      - Draft, 2002 February 17; 2 (Box 153)
      - Draft, proofread by Elizabeth Macklin, 2001 April 13; 3 (Box 153)
      - Draft, with Gould's suggestions (chapters 1-3), 1999 March 15 (Box 153)
      - Draft, with Gould's suggestions (chapters 4-12), 1999 March 15; 2 (Box 154)
    - Dark Harbor
      - Draft with "tentative pic placement", 2002-2003; 2 (Box 154)
      - Draft with Kate Norris and Liz Macklin's changes, 2003 February 26; 2 (Box 154)
      - Liz Macklin's changes, 2003 February 2 (Box 154)
      - Draft (excerpts), undated (Box 154)
      - Draft, Bill Whitworth's, Chuck Verrill's changes, 2002 August 23 (Box 155)
      - Draft, Linn's copy with changes, 2003 January; 2 (Box 155)
      - Draft, 2003 March 14; 2 (Box 155)
    - The Red Letters
      - Draft, final copy minus small edition, undated; 2 (Box 155)
      - Draft, revised, 2002 July 3; 2 (Box 155)
      - Draft, undated (Box 156)
      - Draft, "Latest version?", undated (Box 156)
      - Draft, "Gould copy", undated (Box 156)
      - Different versions, undated (Box 156)
      - Draft, with Liz Macklin edits, 2001 June 21 (Box 156)
      - Drafts, undated; 2 (Box 156)
      - Consolidated (Box 157)
      - Oma's drafts (copies), 2 (Box 157)
      - Father's drafts of manuscripts of love letters, 4 (Box 157)
      - Drafts of manuscripts of love letters, 2 (Box 158)